Software Engineering Manager

Rob Bednark

4 971-276-8789

[™] <u>rbednark@gmail.com</u>

linkedin.com/in/robbednark

🚨 33 Spinosa, Lake Oswego, OR 97035

SUMMARY

4 years experience as software engineering manager, 3 years as team lead, 17 years as software engineer. I focus on solutions, and meet challenges head-on with empathy and compassion, playing the roles of strategist, leader, engineer, and coach.

I believe people-centered work cultures increase employee happiness, resulting in more productive, creative, and sustainable workplaces, and that human interaction (listening, collaborating, encouraging, conflict-resolution, ...) is essential. I'm down to earth, practical, and pragmatic, bringing ideas out of the clouds and into concrete goals and plans.

SKILLS

Languages (recent)

Python, JavaScript, Ruby

Databases

DynamoDB, ElasticSearch, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Solr/Lucene

Tools, Frameworks, Services

Amazon API-Gateway/AWS/DynamoDB/EC2/Lambda/S3/SES, BuildKite, Django, Docker, Git, Grafana, GraphQL, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Node, React, Rails

Methodologies

agile, CI/CD, DevOps, kanban, microservices, MVC, OO, scrum, TDD

Operating Systems

Linux, macOS, Windows

EXPERIENCE

Invoca / Software Engineering Manager

Mar 2021 - Aug 2023 Fully remote

Managed a full-stack development team of 5 direct reports that added new features and maintained several functional areas of the platform. Responsibilities:

- Managed direct reports: hired and determined promotions and raises, weekly 1:1s, quarterly performance reviews, set expectations and addressed performance issues, conflict resolution, personal development plans, managed interns
- **Project management**: coordinated with architects, product managers, lead developers, and UX designers to plan and deliver projects; kept the team focused; assigned roles; mitigated risk and delays; created plans-of-action; created roadmaps (features and technical initiatives)
- **Technical**: 24/7 on-call duty; diagnosed issues; coding; reviewed requirements, UX and technical designs; code reviews
- Tech stack: Ruby on Rails, React, Graphql, Apollo, MySQL, Kubernetes, Redis, Kafka, Grafana, Kibana, BuildKite, AWS

Rob Bednark 2

Sabbatical

Feb 2020 - Feb 2021

 After Moovel announced its shutdown, took a sabbatical to spend time with family and friends, reflect, establish healthy daily habits (meditating, co-learning, co-working, running, journaling, waking early, stretching), learn new technologies, work on apps, and discover activities that I enjoy.

• Emerged with increased and renewed self-awareness, health, and relationships, and sense of purpose and desire for management.

Moovel / Software Engineering Manager, Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2016 - Feb 2020, Portland, OR

Software Engineering Manager

 Directly responsible for hiring, employee reviews, coordinating with product managers and account executives, product delivery, 24/7 on-call duty, and team health for two cross-functional development teams of six and seven direct reports.

Senior Software Engineer

- Created designs and specifications for new features
- Worked on back-end services (Node, Jenkins, docker, MySQL, Postgres, ElasticSearch, Redis, Splunk, Jenkins, automated testing (unit, functional, integration))
- Worked on a web app for viewing and updating catalog data involving many tables and relationships, using journaling and workflows (React, Redux, html, CSS, JavaScript)

🔘 Idealist / Team Lead, Senior Software Engineer

Sep 2015 - Jul 2016, Portland, OR

- 20 engineers, developed high-traffic website for mobile ticketing, 2 million visits per month, 1 million users, 100k paying customers
- Converted site to a front-end / RESTful API architecture.
- Implemented an API for external customers to post jobs.
- Extremely collaborative development environment, with extensive pair programming and mob programming.
- Tech stack: Python (Flask, SQLAlchemy, RabbitMQ), PostgreSQL, Redis, HAProxy, nginx, gunicorn, Bamboo, Lambda, API Gateway, DynamoDB, Linux.

trapit / Senior Platform Engineer

Apr 2014 - Aug 2015, Portland, OR

- Multi-tenanted cloud platform; RESTful API for web and mobile clients
- Services to continuously pull content from 100k+ RSS feeds into multiple databases
- Services for sending email and getting social media share analytics.
- Emphasized performance, scalability, automated testing, and reliability.
- 100k+ RSS feeds, 10k users, 80 enterprise customers, 30 services, and used 100+ PyPI python packages and standard libraries.
- Tech stack: AWS, boto S3, Cassandra, fabric, Linux, nginx, NoSQL, ORM, pillow, pipelines, PostgreSQL, puppet, pystache, RabbitMQ, Redis, RSS, SES, Solr / Lucene, SQL, SQLAlchemy, zmq

Rob Bednark 3

Atlatl / Software Architect, Lead Software Engineer

Jan 2013 - Apr 2014, Portland, OR

- Employee #10 in a 30-person startup
- Software architect and team lead for web application, API's, and database
- Grew from 2 to 8 engineers lead team of 7 other engineers (3 locally and 4 outsourced in Vietnam).
- When I started, software was still in development, and I was actively involved with deploying the project into production for multiple tenants. Championed test automation, code reviews, requirements, architectural designs, configurable features, technical documentation, performance, hiring excellent engineers, automatic test data generation, and logging.
- Tech stack: Django, Python, PostgreSQL, Selenium, factory_boy, Linux, Nginx, Memcached, AWS, Sentry, JSON, test-driven development (TDD)

Tixie / Senior Software Engineer

June 2012 - Jan 2013, Portland, OR

- Added functionality to the webapp, including user registration and profiles, and created processes to calculate and update data.
- Tech stack: Python, Django, Amazon AWS/EC2/S3/SES, Celery, CSS, Fabric, factory boy, HTML, Linux, Memcached, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Sentry, South, SQL

Uncorked Studios / QA Lead (contract)

August 2011, Portland, OR

- Led the QA effort for a high-profile iOS, Android, Mobile Web, and web app.
- Features included Facebook sharing, geocoding, reverse geocoding, geotagging, 2D/3D virtual-reality mapping; upload, display, and playback of video, audio, photo, and text.

Huawei / QA Manager (contract)

Dec 2010 - July 2011, Remote

- Managed the QA for social-networking web app and mobile apps with VoIP, chat, email, and address book features.
- Managed team; recruited and hired; wrote test plan and testcase specifications; wrote a web app monitoring tool and automated tests.
- Remote team across 13 sites in the U.S., England, Ukraine, Russia, and India.
- Oversaw test automation utilizing Selenium, Python, nose, Ruby, Capybara, and Cucumber.

The Portland Upside / Founder, Publisher, Editor

October 2008 - May 2010, Portland, OR

- Started a print and online monthly newspaper of positive stories.
- Attracted 200+ volunteers for writing, photography, and distribution of 9000 monthly printed copies.
- Coordinated and worked on all aspects of the paper: managing volunteers, finding content, selling advertising, editing, layout, printing, distribution, website creation and maintenance.

Rob Bednark 4

Sabbatical

Nov 2006 - Oct 2008, Portland, OR

• Initiated a journalism project, interviewing 27 people; assisted friend with a startup; helped wife self-publish two books.

• Spent time with family, soul-searched, and got a lot of rest and relaxation. Emerged with renewed strong interest in self-awareness, relationships, work, and technology.

IBM / Senior Software Engineer

July 2001 - Nov 2006, Portland, OR

- Independently conceived, architected, and implemented a Python framework for doing distributed, parallel code execution in an environment with an arbitrary number of clients and servers of various platforms.
 - Result: 200% increase in productivity by a team of 10 test engineers writing automated tests, saving the project \$300k.
- Designed and implemented a multi-threaded, multi-process utility to stress-test a file system by randomly reading from millions of files.
- Designed, implemented, and supported a "one-button-test" application for 40 engineers to run sanity tests prior to committing, automating all aspects of setup and running of tests, improving main branch reliability.

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science, minor Human Relations

Honors Program

St. Cloud State University, St. Cloud, MN